我们跑去海边 因为菲比找到一个女人
Phoebe found out about this lady...
她认识她的父母 然后我就不知道了
...who knew her parents,and I don't know what happened.
我是你的母亲
I'm your mother.
莫妮卡开玩笑说 她不会跟钱德这种人约会
Monica joked she wouldn't date Chandler.
他一直很在意 然后我也不知道了
I don't know what happened there either.
罗斯的新女朋友邦妮跑来
Ross' new girlfriend shows up.
瑞秋说服她理了个大光头 然后罗斯和瑞秋接吻了
Rachel gets Bonnie to shave her head. Then they kiss.
现在他得在瑞秋 和光头女之间二选一
Now he has to choose Rachel or the bald girl.
然后我还是不知道
I don't know what happened there either.
等一下，我去找钱德来
Hold on. Let me go get Chandler.
她在帮我搽药，我的头晒伤了
She's helping me. My head's sunburned.
百万份感激 百万份不用客气
-Thanks a million. -You're welcome a million.
你闻
Smell it.
薄荷味的
Minty.
我先回房去
I'll be in our room.
天哪
Oh,my God!
我知道
I know.
好，我走了
I got to go.
什么？为什么？
Why？Why？
我得跟邦妮分手
I got to go break up with Bonnie.
在这里？现在？
Here? Now?
我不能整晚留在这里
I can't stay here all night.
要是我回房，她会想…
If I go in there,she'll want to...
办事的
...do stuff.
你不能说你没心情吗？
Can't you say you aren't in the mood?
她喜欢那样
No,she likes that.
装睡也没用
Faking sleep doesn't work.
我经常早上醒来发现她在…
I've woken up many times with her
我说这个干什么？ 我不知道
-Why am I telling you? -I don't know.
并不是每天早上都… 再描会更黑
-Not every morning -Making it worse!
本集播出：“水母”
The One with the Jellyfish
主演：珍妮佛安妮斯顿
寇妮考克斯
丽莎库卓
麦特勒布兰
马修派瑞
大卫修蒙
你大概想知道前因后果
You probably want to know how it happened.
我猜想得到
I think I can figure it out.
我出生之后 大家都开始撒谎了
I was born,and then everyone lied their asses off.
不是那样的
No,it wasn't like that.
我不是说过 莉莉、弗兰克和我很要好？
Remember how I said Lilly,Frank and I were close?
我们非常要好
We were very close.
多么好？
How close?
我们三个是一对
The three of us were kind of a couple.
三个怎么会是一对
I don't know how that would work.
我们… 我不是在问问题
I'm not asking!
总之，我不知怎的怀孕了
Anyhow,somehow I got pregnant...
我很…
...and I was...
…害怕，我愚昧又自私…
...scared. I was stupid and selfish....
我才18岁 还记得你的18岁吗？
I was 18 years old. Remember what it was like to be 18?
记得，妈自杀，爸跑掉
Mom killed herself and my dad ran off.
我跟一个叫山迪的人住在一辆格里莫林车里 他会跟他的手说话
I lived in a Gremlin with a guy who talked to his hand.
对不起 我以为他们是世上最好的父母
I'm sorry. I thought I'd left you with the best parents.
直到几年前 我才听说他们的事
I didn't hear about them till a few years ago.
当时你已经长大了
By then,you were already grown-up.
既然你来了，我也想多认识你
You're here and I would really like to get to know you.
每个人都想认识我
Well,everybody does.
我是个很酷的人
I'm a really cool person.
你有29年的时间可以寻找 却连试都没试
You had 29 years to find out,but you didn't even try.
你扔下我不管，现在我也要
You walked out on me,and I'll do the same.
等一下
Wait.
我不想再见到你
I don't ever want to see you again.
我的皮包呢？
Where's my purse?
讨厌，没有汽水了
Shoot! We're out of soda.
我去帮你买 真的？
-I'll get you some. -Really?
才怪，我又不是你的男朋友
No,because I'm not your boyfriend.
菲比，怎么样？
Hey,Pheebs,how'd it go?
我妈的朋友菲比 其实是我的亲生母亲
My mom's friend,Phoebe,is actually my birth mom.
我捡到一个干掉的海马
I found a dried-up seahorse.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
我的新妈妈当年抛弃了我
My new mom,who's a big fat abandoner.
菲比，等等 你不坐下来聊一聊吗？
Don't you want to stay here and talk about it?
不了，我想一个人待一会儿
I need to be alone.
莫妮卡
Monica.
要是你发现你妈不是你妈
Man. Hey.....what if you found out that your mom wasn't really your mom...
而你的新妈妈又很辣呢？
...and your new mom turned out to be really hot?
天呐，对吧？
Oh,man,huh?
但她是你妈耶
But,it's your mom.
不，我是在说你妈
No,I'm talking about your mom.
结束了
It's over.
很惨吗？
Was it awful?
很久
It was long.
我没意识到那么晚了
I didn't realize how late it was...
直到她头上出现5点钟的曙光
...till I saw the five o'clock shadow on her head.
她不想留下来 我帮她叫了车，她刚走
She didn't want to stay. I called a cab. She just left.
我写了封信给你
I wrote you a letter.
谢谢
Oh,thank you!
我喜欢收信
I like mail.
我想了一些关于我们的事
It's just some things I've been thinking about. About us.
在我们考虑复合之前
Before we even think about us getting back together...
我得知道你对这封信的想法
...I need to know how you feel about this stuff.
现在是早上5点半
It's 5:30 in the morning.
我最好赶快看完
So I'd better get cracking on this baby.
我等你，看完就上来
I'll be waiting for you. Come up when you're done.
好，我要花…
I'll be up...
十八页的时间
...in 18 pages.
从头到尾
Front and back.
好兴奋喔
Very exciting!
怎么样了？你怎么没上来？
What happened to you? Why didn't you come up?
看完了
Done.
你才刚看完？ 我想看仔细一点
-You just finished? -I wanted to be thorough.
这对你…对我们显然很重要
This is clearly very important to you. To us.
我想一字一句用心斟酌
I wanted to read every word carefully.
斟酌两次
Twice.
所以…行吗？
So…Does it?
什么？
I'm sorry?
行吗？
Does it?
行吗？行吗？
Does it? Does it?
我想再瞄一眼“行吗”的部份
I wanted to give that whole "Does it?" part another glance.
什么意思？你说你看了两次
What do you mean? You said you read it twice.
行不行一句话 如果你还要考虑…
It either does or doesn't. If you have to think
不，我不用考虑，不用
No,I don't have to think about it.
事实上…
In fact...
我已经决定了，我决定…
...I've decided. I have decided...
这件事…
...that it...
行
...does.
你确定？ 确定
-Are you sure? -Sure,I'm sure!
好，发生核爆灾难 我是世上仅存的男人
There's a nuclear holocaust. I'm the last man on earth.
你会跟我约会吗？
Would you go out with me?
我有罐头喔
I've got canned goods.
喂，你们看
Take a look at this!
你们瞧瞧，我挖了个洞
Check this baby out! Dug me a hole.
好棒的洞啊
Excellent hole,Joe.
不！我的洞！
Oh,no! My hole!
我的脚！
My foot!
怎么了？
What is it?
我被水母咬了，好痛…
Jellyfish sting! It hurts!
要不要扶你回去？
Can we help you to the house?
2哩耶
It's two miles.
而且我挖洞挖得好累
And I'm tired from digging.
死水母
Damn the jellyfish!
所有的水母都去死
Damn all the jellyfish!
得想个办法
Do something.
只有一个办法
There's only one thing.
什么办法？
What is it?
在伤口上撒尿
Pee on it.
什么？好恶！
Gross!
别怪我 我是在探索频道上看到的
I saw it on Discovery Channel.
他没唬你，尿液里有氨
He's right. There's ammonia in that...
可以止痛
...that kills the pain.
我不要，其实没那么痛…
Forget it. It doesn't hurt that bad!
为了隐私你可以躲进我的洞里
You can use my hole for privacy.
我准备好要走了
I'm ready to get the hell out of here.
你们…？真的？
Are you?
太棒了
That's so great!
邦妮好可怜
Not for Bonnie.
但恭喜你们了
But for you,yea!
海边好玩吗？ 不怎么样，我不知道
-How was the beach? -Nothing. I don't know.
怎么了？ 没事
-What happened? -Nothing.
我要去冲澡 我也是
-I'm going to shower. -Me too.
我也是
Me too.
我把袋子拿到车上
I'll put this in the car.
我得去收拾东西
I have to go pack!
真的行吗？ 行
-And it really does? -lt does.
真的真的行
It really and truly does.
行你个头！
It so does not!
（中央咖啡馆）
她要我对我们的失和 负起全部的责任
She wants me to take responsibility for everything that went wrong.
她写了整整五页 说我如何不忠
She goes on for five pages about how I was unfaithful to her.
我们当时分手了
We were on a break!
天哪，你再说一次 我就跟你分手
If you say that one more time,I'll break up with you.
分手不是我一个人的错 她说
This breakup was not all my fault. She says here...
“要是你负起全部的责任”
..."lf you accept full responsibility...
“我就能再次信任你”
...I can begin to trust you again.
“你想你办得到吗？行吗？”
Does that seem like something you can do? Does it?"
不行
No
你得偿所愿，跟她复合了
You have what you want. You're back with her.
现在提出来 会毁了你一生中最美好的事
If you bring this up now,you'll wreck it.
我知道，你说得对
Yeah,I know. You're right.
我会就此打住
I'll let it go.
但你们了解这件事很难忘记吧
But you know how hard it is to forget this?
当然很难
Sure,it's hard...
但你不必拿出来谈
...but you don't have to talk about it.
这次度假有很多事 都该从此绝口不提
A lot happened on that trip...that we should never,ever talk about.
在海边到底怎么了？
What happened on that beach?
那是我们和大海的秘密
It's between us and the sea,Ross.
乌苏拉
Hi,Ursula.
我知道我们很久没联络了
I know that we haven't talked in a long time.
但我们的妈妈不是亲妈妈 另一个女的才是
Our mom is not our birth mom. This other lady is our birth mom.
对，住在莫陶克的那个
Right,the one that lives in Montauk.
你认识她？
You know her?
不认识，但妈的自杀遗书里有提到
No. I read about her in Mom's suicide note.
妈有留自杀遗书？还在吗？
There was a suicide note? Do you still have it?
等一下
Hang on.
你居然没告诉我有遗书
I can't believe you didn't tell me there was a suicide note.
是啊，你最近好吗？
Yeah,so how have you been doing?
我…闭嘴
Shut up!
“别了，菲比与乌苏拉” “我会想念你们”
"Goodbye,Phoebe and Ursula. I'll miss you.
“另外，你们母亲住在莫陶克”
P.S. Your mom lives in Montauk."
这是你刚才写的
You just wrote this!
差不多是这个意思
It's pretty much the gist.
只差那首诗，你读过那首诗吧
Except for the poem. You read the poem,right?
没有
No
等一下
All right. Hang on.
请把起司给我
Pass the cheese,please.
你连看都不敢看我，对吧？
You can't even look at me,can you?
对
No
是菲比！我们可以跟菲比说话
It's Phoebe! We can talk to Phoebe!
我很沮丧，不想说话
I'm too depressed to talk.
我给你1千元开口费
I'll give you $1000 to talk to us.
我们要不要每年都回去玩？
What about making that beach trip an annual thing?
不要
No
到底出了什么事？
What happened out there?
什么？ 我们只是去散步，没什么
What? We took a walk. Nothing happened.
我身上什么都没沾到
I came back with nothing all over me.
拜托，到底是…乔伊？
What happened? Joey?
好吧 不行
All right.-No！
我们发誓要死守秘密
We swore we'd never tell.
他们不会了解的
They'll never understand.
我们得说出来，我快被逼疯了
We have to get it out. It's eating me alive!
莫妮卡被水母咬到 好吧
-Monica got stung by a jellyfish. -All right!
好吧
Right
我被咬到
I got stung.
咬得很严重
Stung bad.
站都站不直
I couldn't stand.
走也走不动
I couldn't walk.
我们离小屋2哩远
We were two miles from the house.
既孤单又害怕
We were scared and alone.
我们还以为死定了
We didn't think we could make it.
我痛得要命
I was in too much pain.
我刚挖完洞好累
And I was tired from digging.
然后乔伊想起一件事
Then Joey remembered something.
是在探索频道上看到的
I'd seen it on Discovery Channel.
慢着，我也看过
Wait,I saw that.
是探索频道没错 说要是你被水母…
On the Discovery Channel. About jellyfish and how if you
你在自己身上撒尿？
You peed on yourself?
你不能这么说！你不知道
You can't say that! You don't know!
我都快痛昏了
I thought I would pass out.
我试过，但没办法…
I tried,but I couldn't...
弯成那个姿势
...bend that way.
所以…
So
没错，我挺身而出
That's right. I stepped up.
她是我的朋友，她需要帮助
She's my friend and she needed help.
如果有必要 我也会在你们身上撒尿
If I had to,I'd pee on any of you.
只不过…
Only...
我尿不出来
...I couldn't.
我怯场了
I got the stage fright.
我很想帮忙，但压力太大了
I wanted to help,but there was too much pressure.
所以我找钱德
So I turned to Chandler.
乔伊一直对我大叫 “快尿！快点尿！”
Joey kept screaming at me,"Do it now. Do it. Do it now!"
有时在深夜里 我还会听到那个叫声
Sometimes,late at night,I can still hear the screaming.
那是我在隔壁吓你
Because I do it through my wall to freak you out.
也许你们可以找人谈谈
Maybe there's somebody you guys could talk to.
找谁？ 难道这种事还有团体治疗？
Oh,who?It's not like they have a group for people like us.
有个叫欧文的很厉害
Yeah,no,there's this guy Owen,he's the best.
我有他的名片
Might have his card.
还有紫红色和淡紫色
And fuchsia and mauve
这就是我房里的六十六种颜色
Those are the 66 colors of my bedroom
谢谢
Thank you
大家都回去算算房里的颜色吧
I invite all of you to count the colors in your bedroom.
你除外，你给我滚
Except for you. You go away.
我马上就走
I'll go in a second.
我只想告诉你
I just want to tell you...
我每天都在后悔把你送人
...there wasn't a day I didn't regret giving you up.
好，再见
Okay,bye.
我还没说完
I'm not done.
我之所以没找过你是因为…
The reason I never looked you up was because...
我很怕你的反应
...I was afraid you'd react...
会跟现在一样
...just like the way you're reacting now.
我们不能从现在开始吗？
Can't we just start from here? Please?
不行
No.
好吧
OK
抱歉
Sorry.
最后一件事
One last thing.
你来找你的家人
You came looking for family.
我就是了
I'm family.
没别人了
I'm it.
我说完了
Now I'm done.
我们又没什么损失
It's not like we're losing anything.
你说得对
I guess you're right.
我们又不熟 也没什么共同点
It's not like we know each other or have anything in common.
我不晓得，我们不见得…
I don't know. It's not like...
没有共同点
...we don't have anything in common.
像我喜欢披萨
I mean,I like pizza.
我也喜欢披萨
I like pizza!
是吗？等等，我喜欢披头四
Wait,I like the Beatles.
天哪，我也是
Oh,my God! So do l.
等等，小狗狗可不可爱？
Puppies. Cute or ugly?
可爱死了
So cute!
看吧
You see?
但我还是很气你
But I'm still mad at you.
我知道
I know.
我也很气自己
I'm mad at me too.
你想吃东西吗？我有点饿
Do you want to get something to eat? I'm kind of hungry.
我也是 太不可思议了
Hey! Me too!Uncanny.
好像快下雨了，我没带伞
It looks like rain and I don't have my umbrella.
我也是，真讨厌
Me neither. I really hate that.
够了，你现在只是想吓我
Stop it. Now you're just doing it to freak me out.
我好想你
I missed you.
我也很想你
I missed you too.
我对那封信好紧张
I was so nervous about that letter.
但是你这么坦然认错
But the way you owned up to everything...
证明你真的成长不少
...it just showed me how much you've grown.
大概吧
I suppose.
你有，罗斯，你应该信任自己
You have,Ross. You should give yourself credit.
我妈一直觉得我们无法复合
My mom never thought this would work out.
她说：一次出轨，永不原谅
She said,"Once a cheater,always a cheater."
真希望没有这4个月的空白
I just wish we hadn't lost those four months.
但要是时间能让你看清楚一点…
But if time was what you needed to gain a little perspective....
我们当时分手了！
We were on a break!
喝咖啡？ 好
-Coffeehouse? -You bet.
这段感情会破裂是两个人的错
It took two people to break up this relationship.
对，你和影印店那个女的 你昨天表明愿意负责
You and that girl,which yesterday you took full responsibility for.
我不知道我负的是什么责
I didn't know what I took responsibility for.
我没把信看完 什么？
I didn't finish the letter.
我睡着了
I fell asleep.
你睡着了？
You fell asleep?
当时是早上5点半
It was 5:30 in the morning.
你一废话就废话了十八页
And you had rambled on for 18 pages.
从头到尾
Front and back!
还有 “你”后面加个“re”是指“你是”
By the way,Y-O-U-apostrophe-R-E means "you are."
加“r”是代表“你的”
Y-O-U-R means "your."
我居然会想跟你复合 我们根本就完了
I can't believe I thought of getting back with you! We are so over.
无所谓
Fine by me!
你星期六晚上 跟莫妮卡玩拼字游戏时
Those spelling tips will be handy Saturday nights at home...
一定不会写错字
...playing Scrabble with Monica.
对不起
Sorry!
我只可怜你会想我想到失眠
All that sleep you'll miss wishing you were with me!
别怕我会睡不着
Don't worry about me falling asleep.
我还有你的信
I still have your letter!
顺便告诉你 这种事并不常见
Just so you know,it's not that common.
并非男人都会这样
It doesn't happen to every guy.
这是很严重的
And it is a big deal!
我就知道
I knew it!
金
Gin.
我们在玩金拉米牌？
We were playing gin?
如果我们是男女朋友，可以光着身体玩
If we were a couple,we could play naked.
别再说了。-好吧
-Would you stop? -Okay. All right.
好啦
All right.
我觉得你很棒
I think you're great.
我觉得你人很好，很聪明
I think you're sweet and smart...
我爱你
...and I love you.
但你永远是在我身上撒尿的人
But you'll always be the guy who peed on me.